The writings of Rabash are
article What are the tomes of prayer
and gratitude in the work?
Chazal Amru Our sages
said One should always
establish the praise of the
Creator and then pray.
Chazal Amru They also said Rabbi
Elazar said one should always
establish one's
prayer and then pray one should
understand why we must first
establish the praise of the Creator
when a person is in a state of
deficiency and wants to pray
to the Creator to fill his lack,
then he needs his help.
Thus, why should one first
establish the praise of the Creator?
With a flesh and blood king,
we can understand that first we
must show our respect for the
king so the king will see that
we are among those who love him
and for this reason
the king will grant our
wish but how can this be said
with regard to the creator does
the creator need a person to
show him that he is among those
who love the Creator and then
the Creator will help him and
otherwise he will not.
After all, the Creator is
merciful and gracious.
Although one is unworthy,
the Creator helps
those who pray to Him.
As Bala Sulaim explained,
what we say in the 18th prayer,
you hear the prayer of every mouth,
meaning that it does not
matter what mouth prays,
but the prayer of any mouth.
Even if this mouth is unimportant,
still the Creator hears it
thus why must we first
establish the praise of the
Creator in order to interpret
this we should first present the
words of the
Zohar and
see and it came to pass before he
concluded speaking that behold
Rebekah came
out it asks it should have said
came as it is written Rachel
his daughter
comes why does it say come out he
says that this indicates that
the creator took her out from
among the townspeople who were
all wicked.
And Rebekah came out and was
separated from the rest of the
people in the city
because she was righteous.
Rashi interprets the verse
perhaps the woman does not walk.
He writes, it says, To me, perhaps,
and to me are spelled the same in Hebrew.
Eliezer had a daughter.
He was looking for a reason
that Abraham would turn to him to
marry his daughter.
Abraham said to him,
My son is blessed, and you are cursed.
Cursed does not
cling to the blessed.
should interpret the meaning
of Isaac and Rebekah as well as
the matter of the daughter of
Eliezer in the work the Zohar
writes he said to him my master
shall say if he heard how the
authors of the Mishnah said this
portion which they interpreted
concerning the soul that
Abraham is the soul and Sarah is the
body in this manner we should
interpret the matter of Isaac
and Rebekah as it is written in
the Zohar Rabbi Yehuda said
his mother Sarah.
Since as the form of Isaac
was as the form of Abraham,
similarly Rebekah's
form was just as Sarah's.
This is why it is
written his mother Sarah.
By this we should also
interpret that that Isaac was the soul
and Rebekah the body.
In the order of man's work,
when he wants to achieve
adhesion with the Creator,
he should always walk on two lines,
right and left.
Right means wholeness.
When a person feels
satisfaction in
work and praises and thanks the
Creator for rewarding him with
being among the King's servants,
he sees that he has achieved a
degree in spirituality which
is not so among the rest of
the servants of the Creator.
yet he recognizes his lowliness
and does not know why the Creator
chose him over other people who
have not yet reached this degree
for this reason he thanks and
praises the King and he can observe
what is written serve the Lord with
gladness at that time he has
nothing for which to pray to the
creator to help him since
he feels no length in his
situation however
later when a person
goes to work on the left
line meaning when he
criticizes the state he is in and he sees
that he is flawed in mind and in
heart and even worse he sometimes
sees how immersed he is in self
-love more than usual
sometimes one comes to such loneliness
that he does not want the Creator
to help him out of his lowliness
on the contrary he is angry
that he is not receiving delight
and pleasure from the corporeal
life it follows that sometimes
the left does not let him even
pray and ask of the
creator thus how can he feel
himself as a whole person and thank
the creator
however we must know that the
work is mainly during the ascent
only during an ascent
can we speak of man's
work in two lines right and
left universally during a
descent the person is considered dead
can we say that we are
speaking to the dead or that we want
something from the dead that he
will do something for this reason
when a person is in a state of
work it can be said that a
person should work in two ways 1.
Right 2. Left Right means
primarily that the wholeness in him
is built on above reason while the
left in him is built specifically
on the reason and
intellect that is,
at that time he judges
himself as he sees as our sages said
a judge has only what his eyes
see he turns out that when he
engages in the left and sees the
truth how lowly and
immersed in self
-love he is how can he then say
that he is in a state of wholeness
and be grateful to the
Creator for giving him such a great
gift that he is in Kedushah,
holiness this is the
complete opposite of the truth he
sees how can one be happy when
he sees the truth the answer
is in two ways one it
is written in the
essay concerning faith in his
teacher that Bala Sulaim said
said that a person should go with
faith in the sages,
as they have arranged it for us.
These are his words,
slightly altered.
The student must believe,
as his teacher tells him,
to walk on the path of
right and wholeness.
The student should depict to
himself that he has already been
rewarded with complete faith
in the Creator.
he already feels in his organs
that the creator leads the whole
world as the good who does
good this means that the whole
world receives from him only
good and although when he
looks at himself he sees that he is
bare and destitute and also
when he looks at the world he sees
that the whole world
suffers torments each one
suffering according to his
degree he should say about this
as it is written they have eyes
and see not that is as long as a
person is in a state of they
that they have two authorities
they cannot see the truth for
this reason the person must
believe above reason that he is
in wholeness and so is the
entire world it follows that in this
way he can and should thank the
Creator for giving us abundance.
This is called the right line,
which is the complete
opposite of the left line.
That is, in the left line,
we walk within reason.
As was said, that a judge
has only what his eyes see.
In other words,
it is specifically with the intellect,
and not above reason.
But when shifting to
work with the right,
the left is the cause that the
right is built on the basis of
above reason.
This is as our sages said.
the left rejects and the
right brings closer.
In other words,
the state of left shows a person
how he is rejected and separated
from the work of the Creator.
The right brings
closer means that it shows
him that he is close to
the work of the Creator.
This means that when he
engages in the left,
the left should bring him to
see a state of rejection,
that he is rejected and
separated from the work.
when he engages in the right he
should come to a state where
he sees that he is close to the
creator one should
thank the creator for the
right and pray to
the creator for the
left because only on two
legs a person can walk in
corporeality this
is extended from
spirituality and it shows
that a person should walk on two
lines concerning the
wholeness there is another
manner if a person comes to a
state where he sees that he is
bare and destitute sees since
he is behind both in mind and
in heart meaning he sees
that he is immersed in self
-love and he sees
that he does not have
anything that has any desire to
work for the sake of the creator
now he sees that he has come to his
true state called recognition
of evil he says that the fact
that he now sees the recognition
of evil is a gift from
above that he was shown the
truth otherwise he would deceive
himself and he would think that
he does not need to change his
way since he is
certainly walking on the path of
truth thus he could
remain with his evil
forever but
now a revelation from above
came to him to see the truth this
is as it is written in
the Zohar about the
verse or make his sin down to
him it interprets that the
creator notified him that he has
sinned meaning he was
notified from above that he has
sinned in other words the
recognition of evil is a revelation
from above for this reason he
rejoices at the fact that that
the Creator tends to him and
guides him and shows him his true
state. This gives him wholeness,
meaning from being rewarded
with the revelation of the truth
from the hands of the Creator.
This discernment that he
receives wholeness means that he says
that the creator is bringing
him closer and he shows him the
truth it follows that now he's
not in a state where he says that
the creator has rejected him
from Kedushah because he
feels the bad on the contrary this
makes him
feel that the creator is
bringing him closer which is called
the right brings
closer naturally in that state
when he sees that he is entirely
bad he can overcome and seek
advice how to emerge from this
evil hence he
thanks and praises the
creator it follows that now he
is regarded as blessed in that
he sees that he has received
the knowledge from above about
the recognition of evil when he
thanks the Creator he is certainly
considered blessed since he
received a blessing from the Creator
and then he can come to
adhesion with the Creator since the
blessed clings to
the blessed this is
blessed it is
written in the Zohar and
therefore although Eliezer
was a sage he felt that he lacked
the quality of truth he was
always in the state of the
left and always had grievances
why the creator would not hear
him and give him a
soul since the
light in it reforms him
although the left speaks to the
point since everything is built
on reason as was said that the
judge has only what his eyes
see but in truth he is
cursed this is why Abraham told
him the cursed
meaning the body in a state of
cursed cannot receive the instilling
of the Shekhinah regarded as one's
personal soul.
This is so because the
Shekhinah means Malchut,
which is the
collection of the souls.
For this reason,
Malchut is called the assembly of Israel.
Hence, in this state,
the body is unfit to
receive the quality of Isaac,
who is called a soul it was said
that the body is called wife
and the soul is called husband
however Rebecca means in the
work that the body is everything
that the left shows it it's
true state that all its organs are
wicked that it understands only
that which concerns itself of
that with regard to the
benefit of the Creator it cannot do
a thing just as the left shows
it this is the meaning of all
the townspeople were
wicked since the body is called
a city as it is written a small
city with few people in
it a great king came to
it and found in it a poor wise
man and he saved the city with his
wisdom Rebekah who was a single
righteous woman came out from
among all the townspeople
what does it say came out it says
that it indicates that the
creator took her out from among all
the townspeople this means that
this body felt itself as whole
meaning it's
righteous
because the creator notified
it the truth from this it is glad
and this in itself is regarded
as wholeness that the creator
notified it or for the second
above reason that he believes
above reason that he has
wholeness because he believes in faith
in his teacher that we must go
above reason and say they have
eyes and see not in a state of
wholeness we can be rewarded
with the state of Isaac who is
called a soul this means that
the two opposites are in one body
but in two times we are told that
the most important is to walk
on the right
line once he has a
little bit of the left
line this is the meaning of one
should always establish the
praise of the creator which is
considered right and then pray
regarded as left and then
he returns to the right
how are you doing?
okay a little so we heard from
here the time the time of prayer
and the time of
gratitude the person has
recognition of evil he realizes that
as he writes here he's
wicked and
then the first section that he
needs to do is prayer as I understand
it but then there is a certain
change when he shifts to the
right he's
wicked he made a prayer what
causes him to suddenly shift to
the right the prayer
the very fact that a person
prays already brings him closer
to correct him
correct him brings him
closer in order for a person to
shift after the prayer to the
right line he should also
receive a certain response to the
prayer or the very
fact that he prays is
enough it depends on the
degree of left and right that he's
in what degree
of coarseness he has to show to
the creator from his current
state in the place where we are
the moment a person discovers
that he is in the state of
bad he is wicked, doesn't
want to connect with his friends
everything we understand and
he prays do we have any reason
to delay after the prayer and
go to gratitude or after the
prayer we immediately have to shift
there is reason to
delay typically when we are
ready to pray we already think that
this is it now according to my
words the Creator picks me
up and throws me from one end to
the world to the other or vice
versa it doesn't
matter from end to end meaning I'm
now proceeding in
ascent changes it doesn't
always work this way but a
person needs to go again and
again into a prayer and he has to
feel like he has an opportunity
to incorporate in the friends and
this is called and the Creator,
this is what it means and then
to reach change several times
like that
on the left what does it mean
one should always pray to the
Creator how does one
erase the praise of the
Creator the praise of the
Creator is something he arranges from
what is revealed to him the
Creator is in the right,
in bestowal in
connection then he looks at
himself and he sees that
relative to the creator he's
in the left it says that during
an ascent he's on two lines,
the left and the right
but during a descent he's
considered as dead
which means that there's
no connection between the left
and the descent spirituality
is all built on an
ascent connection is called
right and to divide means
the left the action of the
left but it says that only
during the ascent it's
considered as working on two lines
so the left also can be attributed
to the it can be used for an
ascent if he corrects
the will to receive that
rises onto him then
it means that he's
working on the
left but actually our work is
to reach a state where we work
on two lines all the time in
the direction of the goal
so the very fact that he feels
the recognition of YIVO and he
acknowledges that this is
actually it actually means nearing,
bringing closer it's
a place of work and then a
person sees that he is approaching
Through the revelation of evil,
the Creator is bringing him closer.
He cannot tolerate evil.
He is drawn to cover the
left using the right.
So when is the recognition of
evil considered that he is being
pushed away?
When is it considered that the
recognition of evil brings him
closer? Now is the
time to come closer.
if the creator did not show him
the evil in what way can a person
come closer what will he
cover yes but here he
describes that the very fact that he's
shown the evil is already
considered it is being brought closer
yes even before
he just by the recognition of
evil by itself he already feels
that he's
being brought closer yes what
about blessed and that he's
blessed and he's
in wholeness yes but it's
still not
correction this is still
done by the creator all of
it there is a state when they
reveal the evil to him he feels
that he's
far away and he has to
pray there is also a state
where they show him the evil and
he's grateful and
he feels that he's
near but in both of them they
show him the evil one time he
responds with a prayer
another time he responds with
gratitude so what are these two
states by showing a
person that he's
in the bad and the evil side he's
happy because he has a place of
work and the other
state where he has the evil
but what is he happy he's
praying he's
in prayer he can pray then he's
lacking wholeness but he's
in prayer he's
happy because he has what to
pray for if we take it a bit closer
to our issue for a minute how
can a person when he feels that
he's disconnected far away he's
condemning he's
criticizing etc the friends
and the creator and the goal and
everything how can he
be in a state where he's
happy and rejoicing and say no he's
happy and joyous after he's
made the action of
correction here you're
simply explaining to us the
state this means that he can't
be in a state where he's
happy and rejoicing when
they reveal to him that he's
far away yes but it's
following not simply a joyous
state rather a state that he completed
he made whole he
completed it of course he's
happy but here he
describes a state where the very,
just the fact that the
recognition of evil only in itself the
fact that he was shown
that he is far away,
he is already in a state where
this recognition of evil is a
revelation from above yes,
of course it's
a revelation from
above so how to be in this
state where he is shown the evil,
that he is far away and
already he is in wholeness and in
joy he is still not in
wholeness because when he on
top of the revelation of evil he
draws the power from
above and he raises
himself and then he can be
happy as a result of arranging
the connection between the two
lines How can one not stay as a fool?
What does he depend on?
Using his own powers.
What he went through.
Is this a person's
personal overcoming? Yes.
Yesterday we talked a lot about
the person cannot deliver him
from imprisonment only the
friend can elevate his friend. Yes.
So is it within his own power or
by the power of the friends?
Yes. What do you mean yes? Which one?
You decide. Okay, thanks.
You can give up as far as I'm
concerned. Okay, I give up.
No, guys.
I'm not telling you, seriously,
ask one another, I couldn't
sleep, I couldn't sleep,
because I was so tired,
this congress was very difficult,
very heavy,
I went through it,
but after it was over I felt I
was drained to zero if we're
talking about it already what
makes Rav feel drained exhausted
or not exhausted physical
state first of all truly physical
state as a result of all the
stress and the pressure although
I'm not stressed myself
personally but for some reason when
the action was finished I wasn't
able to do anything not with
my brain not with my heart not
physically, nothing so I'm
waiting for it to pass it's
always like this
following congresses there's
some time that not to that
extent this congress
was way more
powerful so the fact that Rav
is drained is that a good sign
or a bad sign for the
students that's
good you mean for the
students wait and see I think it's
good I think it's
good for everyone it's
a sign that we did work or it's
a sign we were
negligent or sure it's
a sign that there was
work by everyone who were
present and was working it was good
do some reading how to do
it technically what's
the correct way of working in order
to receive the new light that
is coming in the form of these
vessels I think that the most
important is to connect with other
friends and together to already
accept help or bestow maybe a
better way to say it the external
bestowal from other
tents but nevertheless
this way or that way it's
the fact that it's
moving by itself it's
clear but we sit
here we know that it's
going to pass but we also want
to be participating we want to
participate correctly in this
process what did you feel
special in this congress you didn't
feel in past congresses I
felt much more power in the
connection in
shifting from one state to
another that is the people,
the audience that was in the
Congress was an audience that studies,
that undergoes changes and
this is how they went through it
this is the main thing I
felt so what did you mean
by saying it was a little
heavy well it was heavy heavy doesn't
mean bad it's
not that it's
bad but rather heavy it's
like a donkey or a person it doesn't
matter how you say it that
carries a bag full or a sack full
of gold coins on the one hand it
carries it for itself on the
other hand in
between it is hard it's
heavy and from here
on and from here on well it
depends on how much you will be
able to be
flexible in all of these
states and see which state awakens
you and which one doesn't
etc Can you expand about this flexibility?
No, it's better if we speak
from what we are going through.
It would be better this way.
Good. 600 ,000 souls.
It is said that there
are 600 ,000 souls,
and each soul divides
into several sparks.
We must understand how it is
possible for the spiritual to divide,
since initially only
one soul was created,
the soul of Adam HaRishon.
In my opinion,
there is indeed only one soul in the world,
as it is written,
and breathed into his
nostrils the soul of life.
That same soul exists in
all the children of Israel,
complete in each and every one,
as in Adam HaRishon.
since the spiritual is
indivisible and cannot be cut which is
rather a trait of corporeal
things rather saying
that there are 600 ,000
souls and sparks of souls
appears as though it is divided by
the force of the body of each
person in other words first the
body divides and completely
denies him of the radiance of the
soul and by the force of the
Torah and the mitzvah the body
is cleansed and to the extent of its
cleansing the
common soul shines on him
for this reason two
discernments were made in the corporeal
body in the first
discernment one feels one's
soul as a unique organ and does
not understand that this is
the whole of
Israel this is truly a flaw hence
it causes along with the above
mentioned in the second
discernment the true light of the soul
of Israel does not shine on him in
all its power of illumination
but only partially by the
measure he has purified himself by
returning to the
collective the sign for the body's
complete correction is
when one feels that one's
soul exists in the whole of
Israel each and every one of
them for which he does not feel
himself as an individual for
one depends on the
other at that time he is complete
flawless and the soul truly
shines on him in its fullest power
as it appeared in Adam HaRishon
as in he who breathed from within
him what is the first state he
writes about here that one feels
one's soul as an individual and he doesn't
understand it's
the whole of Israel that's
how a person
starts yearning to
understand who am I what am I,
what a soul is,
what the creator is and so
on so in the first phase he
still feels his soul as a unique
detail and he doesn't
understand that that is the whole
of Israel that he has a connection
to the collective of the whole
spiritual vessel that is now
starting to be revealed
to a person and that is a
flaw because it comes from him
feeling his soul as something
that is sliced from the
collective as something
individual and why does he say
that he feels his soul meaning
he already has some
feeling he feels that it's
his internality
but he still doesn't
feel it as a part of a
collective that he's
connected to the collective
he feels that he has it in him as
his soul and he lives and
exists supposedly outside of the
others and in the second state
where he says the true light
of the soul of Israel doesn't
illuminate in all its power
but only partially what does it
mean partially part of that
illumination that shines so he writes,
keep reading by the measure he has
purified himself by returning
to the collective as much as he
connects to the collective in
such a way to that measure he
purifies his soul and he feels
that he's
part of that collective
what does it mean the
state described here
that the soul appears in all
its power as it appeared in Adam
Alishon I don't
know that state itself I don't
attain but according to what
is written you can say that by
man doing that and
connecting to the upper root he can
reveal that light that is
extended upon him from
above well when we connect
with the friends with the points
in the heart we connect with
individual souls or a single
soul we connect to individual
souls between
themselves and the more we connect
we connect them into one one whole,
collective whole.
And the common part,
is that some part of the soul of Adam Arishon?
Yes, of course.
What does it mean 600 ,000
if there's only one soul?
We've learned it, and we'll
learn more about the
shattering of the parzuf.
that is put together from six
parts like Zaranpin that's
why it was shattered into 600 ,000
parts it is
written according to the
measure he was purified the common
soul shines on
him according to the measure who
is purified what is the measure
of purification corrected it's
coarseness of yud and then
what happens then more light can
come from
surrounding light to inner
light and then the general
soul can shine on him there is also
expression here the collective
of Israel what is that
collective of Israel the general soul
what is in him there's
no other division besides the
vessels that are working in order
to bestow according to their
intention their direction they're
called Israel straight
to the creator that's
it the individual that
purifies himself and comes closer to
that collective there's
a collective soul there's
a collective of Israel that
individual starts purifying when
he yes so accordingly that's
how he enters the whole
collective that force of the whole
those who already corrected
themselves in the intention to bestow
and they've
entered a single force with the
Creator and that structure of
the collective that he's
already won he's
already in unity with the
Creator yes so that one that wants
to purify in what what's
the line that brings him to
incorporate in this corrected thing
that he's
already united in the root
of the soul the root of his
soul let's
say now in the
convention some collective
was felt yes what is that force of
the collective that is huge it's
a force what's a force?
a force that attracts towards
the creator the final correction
connection between us all of
it is a force yes First of all,
especially today it
feels like there's
a feeling of what Baal HaSolom
writes in this article and gratitude
that we have such a righteous in
the generation who knows the
entire soul and conveys it in
such a way that there is someone
who knows everything it's
something very unique and he
also knows how to deliver it in
a way that in our generation
we can feel that Rav, yes,
Bar As
-Sulam was awarded with
all the degrees yes it's
felt everywhere
and I wanted to ask,
he talks about the individual who
begins to return to the collective,
so it seems like there's
two aspects here according to
the article and also the feeling
there's the individual who
feels the whole of Israel israel
and basically where is or why
is there a 10 in the way it feels
like it has to be there so the
person can return to the collective
but it's unclear where is it on
the way technically speaking
like a person must have it but it's
unclear where it is between the
individual and feeling the whole
of Israel to its
generations so the individual who
listens to the advice of Kabbalists
about how to return to the
whole that he has to bring
himself to an intention to
bestow as one man in one heart and
so forth so that
individual returns and that is his
correction and what is the
structure of the tent that he's
in maybe it is but where does
the general soul shine on him
specifically during
the tent through the
tent how does a person feel the
collective of Israel and our
generations through the
structure of the tent doesn't
it restrict them we don't
understand how the tent
which seems to us like something
individual and temporary
and coincidental that's
most important that's
what it seems we don't
see that it can actually bring
each and every person to the
goal to a connection to bring
him to his place to his true final
stop yes maybe a strange
question but what is Baal HaSulam's
method what's
the essence of his method
the essence of the method is
truth that there's
nothing besides a force in man
a force in the creator and the
connection between
them to the extent that one can
use his force and the creator's
force that is bestowed
upon him that shines on
him according to that a person
advances towards his source that's
it yesterday when we read none
else besides him so it was clear
that it's like Barasulam's
creation but it's
as our sages said they wrote it's
like he gathers a lot of
things all those things it's
like they concentrate a lot of
sources that already exist what
did he add into there
that makes it a method,
his method because
you feel that there's
something in
him look Bar Suram only
worked in the 20th century before
him many Kabbalists were
active also in his generation
there were a few so you can't
say that this is the one and only
Kabbalist sent by the creator
and that's
it however practically what's
unique about him is that he
received permission from above and
opened to us a very important
part of the wisdom of Kabbalah
that discusses man's
correction which before
Bartholomew was very difficult to understand
to attain and people had to go
through like he explains in one
of the sources you don't
remember the seven wisdoms
yeah the seven wisdoms all kinds
of things like that it's
not simple and for us
essentially basically everyone can come
closer and reach it so he
actually took the whole path and inner
work and he took the essence of
it into something very precise
without all the yes if
you if you read
him word after word in trying
to feel these words a bit from
within then we see he wrote this
to those who wish to feel because
the most important thing is
feeling some people it's
very hard for them
to rise above their
feeling should the tents
conclude the congress they went
through it's
desirable
yeah recommended to discuss in
the tent what we went through,
how we came out of it and what
are we doing next to make it
clear to everyone thank