We'll read a source
excerpt by Baal HaSulam.
When gladness comes to a person,
he should delve in words of
Torah in order to discover the mind
of the Torah.
We must also know that gladness
is an upper illumination that
appears by man.
which is good deeds.
The Creator judges
one where one is.
In other words,
if one takes upon himself the
burden of the kingdom of heaven
for eternity, there is an
immediate upper illumination on this,
which is considered eternity too.
let's read it again when
gladness comes to a person he should
delve in words of Torah in
order to discover the mind of the
Torah we must also know that
gladness is discerned as upper
illumination that appears by man
which is good deeds the creator
judges one where one is in other
words if one takes upon himself
the burden of the kingdom of
heaven for eternity there is an
immediate upper illumination on
this which is considered eternity
too hello dear friends
Hello dear friends It's
very easy to prepare for this
gathering because the preparation
was the Congress two wonderful
days We prepared
together Moscow 2,
Unity 5 and Ekaterinburg and
the last two lessons are like two
points that connected into one
line it shall help his friend
is the point from which we
start and there is no one besides
him is the is the goal I guess
men and women joined together
into this amazing journey where
everything that was before is
finished and a new page is
started for Nebo Uchanim passing
the mic to
Valeo yes we have joy and
gratitude we are all still some on
the way some haven't
yet reached the camera see this
entire wonderful society sitting
together but we're
all together we are all
together again and there is great joy
from the fact that we are
going to hear the sacred words of
our sages once again it's
truly a great
privilege to serve the
friends whoever it is wherever
it is so that we should all simply
feel gratitude for everything
we received and will receive so
Moskva one please our
beloved friends Yes, to continue,
our dear friends after the
Congress I got this feeling,
this impression that I'm
in the first lesson of the
wisdom of Kabbalah the first lesson
I've ever been to and I'm
seeing these huge friends,
thousands upon thousands who
woke up early morning burning with
their desire and yearning
for the Creator and they're
waiting with spiritual fear
for the words of the Creator,
of the Teacher. And a new stage begins,
a new blank page.
And on this blank page,
let us write only about
connections of love, of the good,
mutual integration,
the connection with the friends,
and nothing else.
And from this moment on,
it will be an instrument or a
vessel that the Creator is waiting
for and is in complete
harmony with the light that's
waiting for it. Friends,
yesterday the Congress ended.
Every Congress is a step.
coming closer to our goal,
to the connection between us,
to the revelation,
even if you don't always realize it.
I want to share a little bit of my
impressions from the Congress
that took place.
It turned out that we were on duty,
and during the
duty we went through all the
rooms we saw the study hall some
people in the study hall some
people were on broadcast there
were many people and we leave
the study hall we come to the
kitchen and there are many
people running around this way,
that way doing something,
everyone is working You know,
the density of the friends was
like one friend on a square meter,
even more. So we turned around,
came to the next room.
The women were
peeling vegetables.
Also, a long table,
they sit there shoulder to shoulder,
working and working and working.
And then I simply remembered how
many friends are sitting there
that we don't even see.
The photographers, routers, organizers.
And the question was,
how many people serve the
Congress in order for it to work?
Maybe not less than those who are
actually sitting in the study
hall. then I thought
that in truth it doesn't
even matter it is the same
people those who today were in
the kitchen tomorrow will sit
in the study hall and the
other way around in truth the
congress it's
a living organism it's
one living
body in which everyone wherever
they are give life to this body
they give life to this
congress everyone is required,
everyone is important and
everyone works together the reward
for the friends is the
opportunity to work L 'chaim
friends and thank you very
much second source excerpt
according to the importance one attributes
to the holy work to that extent he
should give praise and thanks
for it this is so because it is
true that we cannot appreciate
the importance of being able to
sometimes observe the mitzvot
of the creator even without any
intention in that state one
comes to feel elation and joy in
the heart and the praise and
the gratitude one gives for it
expands the feelings and one is
related by every single point
in the holy
work and he knows whose
servant he is and thus soars ever
higher this is the meaning of
what is written I thank you for
the grace that you have made with
me meaning for the
past and by this one
can confidently say and he does
say and that you are
destined to do with me
a question for an active
workshop thank the creator
for everything he has done he's
doing and will do for the friends
and for our spiritual advancement
again, active workshop thank
the creator for everything he has
done, he's
doing and will do for the
friends and for our spiritual
advancement we are
after a congress and every
time we have we make a
congress we create it we serve it as
friends and we participate in
it we truly
feel the miracle the creator is
doing for us each one is doing
his own little effort to
participate in the Creator what he's
done and will do in all the
Congresses we participate in he
is making he's
doing this magic this magic of
connection he shows us he demonstrates
his greatness out of our
efforts to connect and our desire to
reveal him and we raise our thanks,
our gratitude to the Creator of
our connection to this force
so that it will continue
towards the correction of the
world I do thank the Creator who
brought us here this morning
it's not something to
be taken for granted,
we should always be
grateful for having the
privilege to sit with the ten before
the Rav and come serve the
society may we connect and bring
the light
yes connect and bring the light
and give thanks like the friends
said to the ten,
to Rav to thank the ten and to
Rav and to Ravash and to Baal
HaSulam and the chain of
Kabbalists who gave us this way,
they wrote the texts
for us and they carry
us truly greatness
of feeling of greatness and
upliftment and importance each and
everyone received we thank
the creator for what he did for
us for giving us a
place to exert we didn't
feel like we are
thieves like we are taking
something for nothing and it's
really an upper force that can
activate the system and give
place for the created beings
and we want to be worthy of it
and we want to merit it and we
hope that the result of all the
exertion we put in is the way we felt
it and give some
contentment to him yes I think we're
not really able to
appreciate what we
received in this congress it's
enough to simply give
gratitude to the Creator because we did
feel the greatness
and importance and
upliftment and there is this
hidden place like Rav said that
this Congress was an important
landmark and it was a complete
force that we were able to draw
to the world a force that
balances so certainly this Congress
was a very important
milestone and for that we need to be
grateful silent workshop let's
now enter a connection in one
heart and feel the creator
there let's
now enter a connection in one
heart and feel the creator