Shalom to you,
thank you for joining me.
We are here with a brief summary
of the series of programs with
Dr. Michael Eitman
and Yael Leshed Arel.
Today in the program we will
try to find a real solution,
a solution from the
root to cyber threats.
For those who are not
familiar with the details,
we are in a time when there are
cyber attacks, cyber wars.
A cyber attack means that we
are using a remote control over
a person's account, an organization's
or a state's account,
in order to destroy their life cycle.
How do we solve this?
This is what I want to
discuss today, a very,
very challenging question.
Let's start with the first part.
Time to wake up, please.
In the past,
we had something to wake up.
There was a record that
you could enter into,
and before that there was a
kind of shield that you could put
in front of your body,
and after that it couldn't reach you.
Today, you're really, really,
really, really exposed.
How do you deal, in your opinion,
how can you deal,
in your opinion,
with this abstract phenomenon?
I don't know what to tell you.
You have a bank of money.
Suddenly, there's a zero.
Or even a minus, let's say. Even worse.
Yes, 50 ,000 dollars.
And you say, no, it can't
be, but there is a fact,
yes, with everything,
in the hospital, everywhere,
suddenly all the medical
supplies are taken away,
they bring you, I mean,
it can be, we are not aware of it.
But if we go into the industry,
nuclear power plants, and trains,
planes in the sky, all kinds of...
It's all controlled by the system.
It's thought. We can't just...
find ourselves here.
How do you deal with it?
This is already known,
what I said. How do we deal with it?
In the end, we cannot deal with
it until we change ourselves.
Because dealing with it is only
possible if the human beings
are good and do not
want to hurt each other.
Or at least not all human beings,
but states, governments,
all kinds of large
organizations that are strong enough to do
this. so at least
those and we will be
able to act for the whole world
as a system of great protection
Is there in the development of
the will of humanity some stage
where the will of the person
will become a will for good?
No So how did it happen?
It was already done by special
education but to decide that we
must We have to live in a world
where everyone is
open to everyone.
We are all connected to each other.
We can all be hurt.
A small child can
hurt the whole world.
Well, theoretically,
but in any case. So we have no choice.
We have to think about what
we are doing in the trial.
Mike Roms, it still
sounds like something very,
very good to me.
What will really cause people,
and certainly governments,
who have some kind of desire to use
all their strength and control
and all these games,
what will really cause them, in the end,
to decide that they want to
act in the direction of good?
To teach in the direction of good?
Fear, fear, and fear of loss,
something big, something important.
What does this mean,
that they will work so that they
really want to start fighting
one with the other and not
control one with the other,
that this is the situation today?
Today it is also so obvious
that you already know, you don't
even hide it. No, it is clear.
If people see that
they have no choice,
and they are
completely dependent on it,
that my life is in the hands of someone,
then there is no choice,
I am looking for how I can be
with him and it is a success.
So there has to be a danger of
life here in order for something
to happen? Yes,
but we have a clear danger of life here.
This cyber is... Is it leading to there?
It's not leading.
It's in terms of the closest,
the most direct to the human life.
To this place,
the complex and the complex,
we arrived by means of
research and development.
We developed from generation to generation,
from year to year,
and we developed technologies
that connect us all today in one
small village, Let's
see the next slide. I mean, what is it?
This cyber exists because
someone implements it.
I can implement it for good,
I can implement it for bad.
So who does it depend on?
On a person, on human beings.
So you're
saying that the change...
On a person's character,
on his development level.
So you're
saying that this is the only
solution that you can see at the
moment? There is no
other solution.
If I stand,
I already said this to Oren,
if I stand and I have the
possibility to press the button and
do what I want in the world,
or this, or that,
or all kinds of things.
That's it. So I press.
So I press the button
and give an order.
Please destroy this city,
but before that,
send me pizza and cola.
What will cause us... That's it.
Instead of
developing today all kinds
of technological or
commercial ideas,
what will cause us as a human
being to develop good human beings?
That this will be our
next development,
instead of developing all kinds of...
So they have to do it.
There is such a program called
Kabbalah that can teach people
to be good people and to
inspire them and to influence them
and to change the whole human society.
What is it? It exists.
And it is really waiting
for such a situation in
humanity And what
would make it possible,
what would be the motivation of people,
of countries,
to live in peace,
to do good to each other?
What would be this
inner motivation?
Oh, this is a completely
different inner motivation.
It's not just to live well in
this world and to enjoy all kinds
of things in silence and in peace,
that you have a
family and children.
We don't want a family, we don't
want children, we don't
even want to live. And that remains,
you say? These are nonsense.
By changing our nature,
we are moving to another life,
to a different dimension.
Because in our dimension,
we have already been blinded.
We don't want to live at all.
I include all my life that I live in.
you know how many people in the
world are in depression and
want to get rid of this life
and they are getting rid of it
with as much joy as possible so
they go to Samis it's like that,
they exist,
there is no
choice but the change of
nature of man is not only that gives
us the security to exist it doesn't
matter for this
security it doesn't
matter to
exist I need to show people
that they have a new age a new
level What kind of world?
We will see an endless world,
a perfect one,
where there will be endless
opportunities and abilities,
and everything
before everyone else.
What I understood is that the
world we love is the result or
the reflection of who
we are as human beings.
It turns out that if we change
ourselves as human beings,
we will also receive
a different world.
Let's see in the next section
how Rabbi Leitman continues to
develop this amazing idea.
He enjoys the fact that he
influences and gives to everyone
instead of receiving
and collecting. Why?
Because then he is not limited.
Because in the
houses that I receive,
there is a limit to how
much I can receive.
In food, money, family,
money, how much can I receive?
I am very limited.
In the end, from the fact that
I am trying to kill myself,
I die. But for a person who lives
in the direction of influence,
he is not limited.
Because you can influence,
from your life you have no end.
And therefore you can enjoy the
influence in an unlimited way.
A person who advances to the level of
this recognition and understanding
of reality,
is he in your eyes the same good
man you talked about earlier,
First of all,
he can only protect the world.
As long as we are good in ourselves,
then this world will be
a safe place. Right.
Now, I understood the
perception of the world of one person.
Let's be a little more careful.
A society that has good people in it.
Yes. How does it function?
A world that has good people in it.
How does it function?
What is it different
from our world today?
They function in a friendly way,
this, this, this, this.
That everyone gives to everyone
and everyone keeps everyone.
And then they are in a state of
general love between them,
and then they create between
them such an area of love that
gives them the
feeling of the next level,
that they live in
giving and love, and don't
need to get anything at all.
How do we use the cyber space?
You want to connect with
everyone in the most open program that
can be, and to connect
with everyone so that
the connection will be
completely open between everyone,
And everyone will become one brain,
one will, one promotion.
And all humanity,
in its individuality, will disappear.
And every person will feel
everything that is in everyone.
That is, he will be boundless.
Is there also a heart in this story?
Or is it all just
rational and cold and magic?
Everything is in a feeling
and in a brain, together.
Shiluv, so in the end,
I have to say more, so in the end,
the human beings
become so connected.
They become human, like there was once,
one will, one thought,
one feeling, one person,
and divided into many parts,
to human beings.
Again, these people connect
together in one desire, in one thought,
in one heart. And that's
what exists in complete. Another question.
What would be the result of
this situation where they're
all connected like one?
No child will get up and press
enter and do this. Exactly.
Because the general idea
that we have in our eyes,
communication and love,
is that he will hold
everyone to be like that.
This is a kind of anti
-virus.
This is a general field of anti
-virus. The general field of
communication and love is to keep
us safe. Happy life. All the best.